MARIO V.

Colorado

Voice: (719) 555-5555 email:mariovemail

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Over nine years of progressive SharePoint administrative, development, training and analyst experience in the defense and financial services industry. Extensive experience with SharePoint 2007/2010/2013/Office 365 platforms. Used CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, and HTLM languages to customize and enhance user experience with SharePoint. Experienced with Microsoft SharePoint Designer 2007/2010/2013, Microsoft InfoPath Designer 2010/2013, Microsoft Excel 2010/2013, Microsoft Office Suite, PowerApps, Flow, Adobe Creative Suite 4/5/6, Metalogix Content Matrix, Nintex and Dell Quick Apps software.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

DSoft Technology Company - February 2016 to Present (Senior Consultant)

- Provide administrative, development, training and analyst support for all in house SharePoint projects
- Administer Air Force Space Command's Space/Cyberspace Analysis Resource Portal
- Cybersecurity Liaison for Headquarters Air Force Space Command
- Develop custom SharePoint applications to help automate accounting processes
- Organized and performed an Office 365 to Office 365 data and user migration
- Designed SharePoint business intelligence tools to help analyze accounting data
- Responsible for SharePoint content migration and application development for the Department of Commerce
- Designed custom forms and workflows for DSoft construction clients
- Created and administered Office 365, SharePoint 2010 and SharePoint 2013 systems
- Manage Office 365 licenses and subscriptions
- Performed baggage handling system tests/analysis for the Transportation Security Administration
- Cultivate new client relationships
- Retain and mature exisiting client relationships

The North Highland Company - November 2015 to February 2016 (SharePoint Consultant)

- Converted excel based processes over to a SharePoint business solution to reduce data validation time
- Developed user guides for administrators and users to help familiarize users with the SharePoint environment

Teksystems (T Rowe Price) - July 2015 to October 2015 (SharePoint Analyst)

- Transformed lists to forms using InfoPath and Nintex to automate the job request process
- Conducted one on one training sessions for company power users to help reduce dependency on IT department for training
- Transitioned excel based processes over to a SharePoint solution to reduce processing time
- Developed online dashboards pages for management to track project activities (live data streaming)
- Configured SharePoint search web parts to automatically display user specific content
- Collaborated with local and satellite business units to complete projects
- Produced SharePoint training videos to ease end user adoption

Serco - November 2010 to July 2015 (Corporate SharePoint Analyst)

- Managed Colorado Springs SharePoint staff, projects and trouble tickets
- SharePoint subject matter expert lead for corporate projects in North America, Europe, Middle East, and Australia
- Co-Authored SharePoint governance documentation for North American division
- Designed portal sites & security structure for multiple 2007, 2010, 2013, and O365 SharePoint environments
- Responsible for the maintenance, management and day-to-day operations of SharePoint for 23,000 users
- Interpreted functions and technical specifications, and systems design to recommend and implement innovative custom solutions
- Responsible for permissions set up and audit, document libraries, and content management
- Provided UI elements customization including, out-of-the box web parts, InfoPath forms, workflows and imagery design

- Assembled dashboards using SharePoint Designer, Excel Services (Power View/Power Pivot), Visio Services and Performance Point Services
- Responsible for SharePoint collaboration project management; provided interface between the users and the developers
- Guided and trained users on platform best practices; end-user incident resolution, problem analysis and customer support

HQ Air Force Space Command - June 2008 to October 2010 (SharePoint Site Manager)

- Responsible for the governance, maintenance, and administration of SharePoint sites and portals for 1,000 users
- Designed, developed and maintained customized components; workflow, InfoPath, navigation, branding, web
 parts, and dashboards; OOTB SharePoint features and functionality
- Provided content management for pages, documents, enterprise lists, libraries, subsites, workflow
- Establish and maintain customized and general permissions; 500+ users
- Provided end user support and troubleshooting
- Liaison between internal / external customers and developers

US Air Force Active Duty and US Air Force Reserve - 1997 to 2017 (Electrical Systems Craftsman)

- Performed crisis management duties for Air Force civil engineering squadrons to ensure co-workers and base populace were informed of the status of electrical system outages
- Coordinated the construction of 30+ business facilities involving numerous departments
- Managed department personnel schedules, purchases, team assignments, and labor activities
- Developed and supervised department hazardous material and safety programs

EDUCATION

• BS-Management/Marketing, Park University, MO

CERTIFICATIONS

• Securty+ (Dec 2014) Exp. Date: Dec 2020

CURRENT SECURITY CLEARANCE (Feb 2018): TS/SCI (Department of Defence)